Mobile +65 9188 9266

Shekleong@yahoo.com

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS:

- Chartered Accountant of Singapore
- Certified Practising Accountant of CPA Australia
- Bachelor of business in Accountancy from RMIT (SIM)
- Diploma in Accountancy from Ngee Ann Polytechnic



OVERVIEW

I have over 20 years working experience in accounting and finance in both commercial and industrial. I'm a Chartered Accountant (CA), a hands-on professional with regional exposure particularly in greater China. I'm hardworking and perseverance as I obtained my Bachelor of Business in Accountancy in Year 1998 during my course of work and continue improving myself by pursuing professional qualification and achieved CPA status in Year 2006. I can work independently and possess leadership to lead the finance team in resolving daily operational and financial issues. My overseas experiences have not only equipped me with an analytical mindset, both my interpersonal and communication skills are also enhanced where I acquired the abilities to deal successfully with cross cultural and regional issues.

CARREER OBJECTIVES:

Seeking a challenging and rewarding position in an organization which provides a dynamic working environment and career advancement opportunities as well as a career to develop myself to the fullest potential as a professional, in an effort to contribute to society.

CORE COMPETENCIES:

- **Leading & Developing** the Finance Team & Succession.
- **Set up accounting system from scratch** and provide advice to management on FRS, Tax.
- **Budget and forecast preparation**, monitoring of actual financial performance against budget or quarterly forecast with variance analysis.
- **Group consolidation**; prepare/review correct and essential group consolidation financial reports for auditing and other use such as prospectus.
- **Implementation of control procedures** to minimize risk, improve operational efficiency and to achieve higher level of data integrity and completeness.
- Cashflow planning & management for different entities located in different area to minimize financial risk.
- **Tax planning** by managing corporate and transitional tax to minimize business costs and to lower the effective tax rate for the group.
- Oversea exposure, leading finance team in various offices in PRC.

Mobile +65 9188 9266

■ Shekleong@yahoo.com

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

(1) ASIA AGRICULTURAL HOLDINGS PTE LTD (ASIA AGRI)

(MAY 2012 – AUG 2016) GROUP FINANCE MANAGER

Asia Agri is a leader in navel orange production in China, with all of its plantations located in Ganzhou, Jiangxi Province. Apart from navel orange business, it is also involved in ancillary businesses, including the farming and sale of pig and chicken livestock as well as cultivation and sale of vegetables.

I joined Asia Agri as Group Finance manager in 2012 reporting to Chairman/CEO and CFO. However, due to downsizing as a result of withdrawal of application for the listing of the Company on the Main Board of SGX-ST in Year 2014. I was then reporting to Chairman/CEO and handled all finance and administrative matters till finalization of accounts in Year 2016.

My responsibilities were:

- Overall in charge Group finance functions including consolidation, statutory reporting, costing, budgeting & forecasts with variances analysis.
- Produce timely reports for the management and the equity investors.
- Coordinate the annual Group audit by performing pre-audit detailed review, answering to queries from Group auditor, ensuring clean audit opinion and signed audit report.
- Preparation of Board papers and attend the Board of Directors meeting.
- Coordinate with overseas subsidiaries on the timely submission of all financial and management accounts.
- Review work processes, policies and procedures, identify areas of improvement.
- Group Cashflow planning & management to minimize liquidity risk.
- Ensuring group's compliance in accounting and other regulatory requirements.
- Preparation and filing of quarterly GST reporting,
- Preparation of the prospectus as well as coordinate roadshow materials and assist in addressing the questions from the IPO working group, private equity investors.
- prepare both partial and full XBRL for filing of Annual Return
- Liaison party with the IPO working group, private equity investors, bankers, internal and external auditors, valuers, company secretarial, tax agent and government agencies.

Achievement:

- Fast learner to pick up adequate knowledge on the operation and independently setup the consolidation templates and forecast worksheets for group reporting and prospectus updating purposes.
- Provided good financial analysis and reliable forecast which were particularly important inputs for the IPO purposes.

Mobile +65 9188 9266

Shekleong@vahoo.com

(2) IPACS CHINA PTE LTD (JUL 2006 TO AUG 2011) SENIOR FINANCE MANAGER

IPACS, a SME, is a full-fledged information technology service provider which provides a comprehensive suite of services with clients mainly in PRC. It offers solutions and services in Systems and Technology Infrastructure, Industry Business Applications and IT services. It is a leading business partner of IBM. Its blue-chip customers include Shanghai Stock Exchange, CITIC Industrial Bank, Beijing Bank, Pufa bank, Shanxia Electrical Power Corporation, Civil Aviation Authority of China.

I joined IPACS as Finance manager in 2006 to lead the finance and contract execution (FCE) team in Singapore as well as in the overseas subsidiaries in Beijing and Shanghai.

My main work scopes include:

- Timely preparation of Group Consolidation management reports in accordance with SFRS.
- Prepare management meeting materials and present in monthly management meeting.
- Cashflow management by moving funds and secure credit facilities if needed to minimize financial risk.
- Conducting regular internal audit to ensure effective internal controls and process established and to recommend measures for improvements and strengthen internal controls.
- Coordinate the annual Group audit by performing pre-audit detailed review, setup consolidation package & deadlines, answering to queries from Group auditor, ensuring clean audit opinion and signed audit report.
- Tax planning by managing corporate and transitional tax to minimize business costs and to lower the effective tax rate for the group.
- Develop and maintain systems for recording, accruing and analysing all items of income and expenditure and reporting these, as appropriate to the Chief Executive Officer, Division Heads and Heads of Department.
- Assist departmental managers in the preparation of annual budgets and targets.
- Regular project cost review with project team for the accuracy of project financial, this includes monitoring, analytical check & review and establishes a review procedure.
- Review month end closing activities includes cost check; cost accrual, work-in-progress and project revenue recognition.
- Reviewing of sales and suppliers' contracts to minimize contractual risks, monitor contract status in delivery, document preparations and follow up on collection progress.
- Monitoring of payments in accordance with contractual terms and to obtain banking facility and trade financing such as letter of credit and performance bonds,
- Monitor usage and availability of banking facilities (Overdraft, letter of credit, trust receipts, banker's guarantees and term loans).
- To act as a liaison party with bankers, auditors, company secretarial, tax agent and other agencies.
- Establish good banking relationships and manage liquidity, interest rates and foreign exchange risks.

Mobile +65 9188 9266

■ Shekleong@yahoo.com

Achievement:

- Able to pick up adequate knowledge on contract execution, by arranging financing, letter of credit, handling of shipment from US to China via Hong Kong without any classroom training.
- Built up from scratch the contract execution status worksheets and transfer to in-house application software.
- Led the team to generate the financial numbers for closing of accounts for PRC subsidiaries and Singapore entity due to change in financial year-end.
- Identified cost savings initiatives to support the business in delivering the numbers.
- Ensured business compliance with Group policies and procedures, refined financial delegations, setup new procedures and controls to govern sales contracting.

(3) SEMBCORP ENGINEERS AND CONSTRUCTORS PTE LTD (MAR 1993 - MAR 2006) SENIOR ACCOUNTANT

I joined SembCorp Engineers and Constructors Pte Ltd (SEC), a wholly owned subsidiary of SGX listed conglomerate; SembCorp Industries (SCI) in 1993 as an Accounts Assistant.

A) Full set of accounts and system implementation (Mar 1993 – Apr 1998) (Accounts Assistant, Accounts Executive, Snr Accounts Executive)

- Handled Sembawang-Multiplex Joint Venture full set of accounts and projects Accounts payables.
- In-charge of accounting system upgrade to capture GST and SAP system implementation.
- In-charge and set-up of various Joint Venture projects (Singapore and Bintan) accounts and system

The following were my relevant post-graduation experiences and responsibilities with the company.

B) Overseas experiences (PRC) (May 1999 – Jul 2003) Finance Executive

- Assist departmental managers in the preparation of annual budgets and targets.
- Preparation of annual business Budget, mid-year review and quarterly forecast.
- Responsible for timely submission of management & financial reports.
- Preparation of variances reports and to investigate abnormal and unusually items.
- Cashflow management, arranged project financing to meet operational needs.
- Tax planning to minimize business costs.
- Compliance of local statutory requirements.
- Corporate secretarial work including preparation of Board Resolutions.
- Preparation of Board papers and present in board of directors' meeting.
- Implementation of processes and procedures to comply with group policies.
- Liaison with auditors, local tax bureau, bankers, lawyers and consultants.

Mobile +65 9188 9266

■ Shekleong@yahoo.com

C) Group reporting and Treasury (Jul 2003 – Mar 2006) Snr Accountant

- Group reporting using Frango Consolidation software.
- Preparation of group annual plan. Mid-year review and quarterly forecast with variances analysis.
- Preparation of descriptive, management & financial reports for management.
- Preparation of reports to meet holding company (SembCorp Industries)'s SGX listing requirements.
- Group cashflow management and treasury management.
- Liaison with external auditor and bankers.
- Assist in preparation of Board papers for the Board of Directors' meeting.

Achievement:

- Awarded company's bursary with 3 years bond for my degree course in view of my good performance.
- Able to cultivate a discipline for planning and budgeting, organised thoughts in work, developed multitasking, problem solving, sharp analytical and interpreting ability.
- Driven and hands on personality, hence minimise disruption to operation when there was internal reorganisation.
- Successfully implemented GST reporting in 1994.
- Led Project Accountant for various Joint Venture projects in Singapore and Bintan. Such as Four Season Hotel, MRT North East Line and Bintan Lagoon Resort.
- Successfully setup accounting and costing system using SAP in a Joint Venture Company with Kumagai Gumi.
- Successfully dealt with Joint Venture partner, respective relevant authorities and led the finance of a Joint Venture company in Tianjin and also a number of projects in Shanghai, Beijing, Guangzhou, Wuxi and Suzhou, with the implementation of financial delegations, policies, procedures and controls.

OTHER INFORMATION

• Gender : Male

Nationality : Singaporean
Marital Status : Married
Last drawn Salary : \$7,800
Expecting Salary : \$8,000